# Baah Lawrence Darko







#### **SUMMARY**

Software Developer with over 5 years of experience in Java/JS, C++, React and React Native, Python. Experienced in leading and collaborating with teams in Agile environments. Notably, I worked on a research project that received a \$15 million funding from USAID, serving as a key member of the development team. Proficient in machine learning and AI, Django, data structures, Git, MySQL, algorithm design, and web/app development.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **B.Sc. in Physics (Computing Option)**

Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology



2017-2021 **Q** Kumasi, Ghana

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Senior Software Engineer**

2023 - ONGOING PIINVENT SOLU., Amsterdam (Netherlands)

- Software Development Engineer at IInvent Solutions, working on critical projects and multiple products at scale
- Building generational products using cutting-edge Cloud platforms such as Google Cloud and Amazon Web Services
- Anticipating customer needs and empowered to act like an owner, act
- Versatile, displaying leadership qualities and enthusiastic about taking on new problems across the full stack
- Designing and writing source code to implement End-to-end Customer experience on IInvent products in collaboration with UX/UI Design teams
- Creating and developing quality and admission controls for software that are deployed on Cloud platforms: Google Cloud, Amazon Web Services and Microsoft Azure
- Supporting Site Reliability Engineering Teams in the creation of Pipelines to collect and assess data
- Working with the Solutions Build and Site Reliability Engineering team to establish robust engineering practices to maintain the quality of products.

### **Team Lead and Scrum Master**

2022 - ONGOING CARISCA Lab, Kumasi (GH)

- Led a team of adept programmers in developing innovative solutions to supply chain problems in Africa
- Successfully ideated and developed game-based learning solutions resulting in a 25% increase in adoption rates of supply chain solutions in Ghana and beyond
- Gamified supply chain concepts to make learning easy and fun

#### **SKILLS**

Machine Learning & AI • Git & GitHub Data Structures • MySQL • AWS Algorithm Design • Web & App dev

#### PROGRAMMIG & FRAMEWORKS

Pvthon • C++ • Java • HTML & CSS • React • JavaScript • React Native • Django

Development & Operations

Agile • Scrum

PROJECTS (• Done -> Next Project \*Ongoing)

 Modeling the Calendaring Process of a Li-ion battery using Machine Learning

₩ 2020 - 2021 RNUST, KUMASI Support Vector Regression-based model for predicting electrode properties

A School Management System

2019 PKNUST, KUMASI https://www.kbbintl.com/

A full-stack school management system that has different login outputs for the administrator, staff and students

A P2P online market system

2019 PKNUST, KUMASI Facilitates marketing among persons

 Store Management System Desktop app (refer to GitHub)

Slack Clone

https://www.slack-clone-proj-779f9.web.app

Netflix Clone

https://lawrenceflix.netlify.app/

### **Teaching and Research Assistant**

- Facilitated discussions and tutorials, assisting students in understanding their course
- Graded course assignments, projects, and lab assignments
- Maintained accurate records and distributed reading materials for students
- Improved student performance by 15% through effective teaching methodologies

### **Senior Developer**

Luminosity Lab 2020 - ONGOING Tempe, Arizona (USA)

- Designed and built algorithms that provided solutions to multiple problems
- Authored code fixes and enhancements for inclusion in future code releases and patches
- Maintained mobile applications and other interesting projects
- Contributed to USAID and CARISCA meetings resulting in successful project development

## Web and Mobile App Developer (Freelancer)

Accra 2019 - ONGOING Accra, Ghana

- Provided software solutions to corporate institutions, schools, and individuals
- Modified existing software to correct errors and improved its performance
- Trained users or clients to use new and modified software
- Increased revenue by 20% through effective client management

### **Lead Developer**

- Led the development of a noise pollution control device in the region's capital Kumasi, Ghana, for the Kumasi Municipal Assembly (KMA)
- Created a website for the organization
- Executed different projects that benefited society and improved livelihoods
- Improved operational efficiency by 30% through effective team management

## **Instagram Clone**

Mobile app (refer to GitHub)

- \* Amazon Clone
- \* Tinder Clone
- -> Spotify Clone (Mobile)

#### **STRENGTHS**

- · Critical Thinking and problem solving
- Teamwork and Collaboration
- · Professionalism and strong work ethics
- Oral and Written Communication skills
- Leadership

### **LANGUAGES**

English – Native Language Spanish – Beginner

### CERTIFICATION

2021 💡 Kumasi, Ghana

Optic Fiber Splicing - Johvic FiberTech Solutions